Sandra García

Nationality Spanish

Contact Details Email: sandra.garcia@insead.edu Mobile: +34 646 69 35 69

SUMMARY

Case Team Leader at Bain & Company with more than 6 years of experience as Management Consultant and M&A/Private Equity Lawyer. Experience across industries with focus on Private Equity, Consumer Products and Retail and across geographies both in developed and emerging markets (Europe, South East Asia and India). MBA from INSEAD and LLM from IE Law School.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2015 - **Bain & Company** Top tier management consulting firm

Europe / South East Asia

Present

Case Team Leader, Private Equity, Consumer Products & Retail Practice Groups

Private Equity Practice

- Advised private equity funds on commercial due diligences across sectors (e-commerce and corporate services) and geographies (Europe and South East Asia)
- Analyzed market trends and competitive position in the context of commercial due diligences; assessed and modelled market projections and target's top line and bottom line upside potential

Corporate Projects

- Designed the growth strategy for leading consumer products companies; identified and modelled the impact of growth initiatives within different brands/products
- Performed store revenue and profitability analysis across >1000 outlets for the retail business of leading South East Asian oil & gas company; optimized store distribution and dealer terms (full potential +70% store revenue)
- Advised major retailer on a comprehensive 5-year strategic plan to improve sales and profitability; analyzed store footprint and defined growth potential across categories
- · Advised consumer products companies on brand definition, assortment optimization and commercial spend
- Defined the premium loyalty program for a major retailer (10% sales increase)
- Defined optimal grocery model for leading European department stores assessing market and customer trends
- Advised leading tobacco company on the improvement of its internal tool to manage trade marketing, marketing and sales functions; led diagnostic and implementation across markets
- Worked with executive management and aligned different stakeholders within major retail and consumer products organizations on strategic decisions and prioritization of initiatives for growth and value creation
- Led workshops with >30 executives to prioritize growth initiatives for major companies

2009 –13 Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer LLP Top tier international law firm

UK / Spain

Associate, Corporate Practice Group (Private Equity/M&A/Finance/Capital Markets)

- Worked on transactions leveraged buyouts (advising both industrial sellers and private equity buyers) across sectors including e-commerce, TMT, energy, consumer and infrastructure ranging from €100m to over €1bn value. Selected transaction experience includes:
 - Advised Amadeus IT Holding on the sale of Opodo to Permira and AXA Private Equity
 - Advised Triton Partners on the acquisition of Befesa Medioambiente
 - Advised EQT Infrastructure Partners on the acquisition of Acciona Aparcamientos
 - Advised Liberbank on the sale of Telecable to Carlyle
 - Advised a major European family office on the acquisition of a solar power company
- · Drafted and negotiated M&A documentation including term sheets, SPAs, SHAs and NDAs
- Coordinated and conducted legal due diligence on companies across industries; analyzed the corporate and financial structure, material agreements and their impact on the relevant transactions
- Coordinated multi-jurisdictional and multi-disciplinary teams of bankers, accountants and overseas counsel to provide integrated advice to clients in corporate and finance transactions within aggressive timeframes
- Interacted on a regular basis with the management team, directors and shareholders of the clients and target companies in the context of M&A transactions and assisted with board of directors' and shareholders' meetings
- Advised on project finance (renewable energy projects); drafted and negotiated facilities agreements and securities over assets

2014 (summer)

Aditya Birla Retail (Intern) *Retail business of the second largest Indian conglomerate*

India

- Developed a market opportunity assessment and screening of potential businesses; identified two fast-growing opportunities (8% and 16% revenue growth)
- Developed the business plan and go-to-market strategy and defined the implementation across regions

EDUCATION

Present

2014 INSEAD MBA Class of December 2014
2008 -09 IE Law School LLM Corporate Business Law. Graduated with Distinction - top 5%

Singapore / France Spain

2003 –08 Universidad de Oviedo/Helsinki University Bachelor of Laws - top 5%

Spain / Finland

LANGUAGES Spanish (Native), English (Fluent), French (Business)

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2012 - Fundación Recover (Volunteer) NGO focused on improving the health system in Africa

Cameroon / Spain

- Conducted several projects aimed at improving the profitability of hospitals in Cameroon
- Led different fundraising initiatives aimed at providing medical equipment for hospitals in Africa

2009 -13 Freshfields Pro-Bono Group (Social Impact & Pro Bono)

UK / Spain

 Member of the Pro Bono Group advising leading non-profit organizations and charities on corporate and financial matters; Advised The Global Fund to fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria in Ecuador on the development of the Debt2Health Initiative